ISAAC PEREIRA

SENIOR BACKEND SOFTWARE ENGINEER

INFO

Address Luís Bandeira, 5,

Santos Dumont, Vila Velha, ES, 29109600, Brazil

Phone +5527988832834

Email pereira.zc@gmail.com

DATE OF BIRTH

1987-03-16

NATIONALITY

Brazilian

SOCIAL PROFILES

Linkedin

linkedin.com/in/pereirazc

Twitter

twitter.com/pereirazc

Github (Personal)
github.com/pereirazc

Github (Side project)
github.com/pextralabs

SKILLS

JBoss Drools

Java

Scala

Play Framework

Akka

JPA

Design Patterns

Gitlab CI

Docker

DigitalOcean

Internet of Things

Wireless Sensor Networks

Android Development

PROFILE

I'm a Software Engineer with 8 years of development experience and R&D skills, soon-to-be **MSc** in Computer Science. I've been building backend services for the insurance market since 2010 and more recently for the IoT market on my own company (<u>Multicast</u>) started as a side project.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Co-Founder and CTO, Multicast IoT

Vitória, ES, Brazil

Oct 2015 - Present

<u>Multicast</u> is a young IoT company who provides an end-to-end solution for monitoring products, equipment, supplies, environments or whatever for analytics and automation of business and industrial activities aided by sensor-data. A service so-called *Multicast* SenseUp.

For the SenseUp my role has been of proposing and delivering features for the mobile apps and the analytics dashboard, designing app and sensor-faced APIs, and mainly, the development of a scalable data-reasoning cloud engine architecture to handle complex integration/automation rules using technologies like Akka, Play Framework and Drools/SCENE.

Leading a freelancer-based team towards the development of the SenseUp apps (PWA, iOS and Android).

Systems and Data Analyst (Part-time), Evológica Tecnologia e Pesquisa

Vitória, ES, Brazil

Feb 2011 - Present

Evológica and, mainly, its branch <u>Idexa</u> have expertise in the modeling, development, and support of Insurance Systems.

My activities and achievements at Evológica involves:

- Backend Framework development/support (Curio Evológica's in-house framework)
- Leading dev teams towards development of products for the insurance market, like <u>eSegurado</u>
- Acting as Mobile Software architect, successfully integrating a multiplatform (Android, iOS) code base under the same conceptual architecture - MVVM, Reactive Clean Architecture (eSegurado)
- DevOps experience engineering CI/CD workflows for an automated QA environment (Docker, Rancher, Nexus, Gitlab CI)
- Designing of internal Dev Tools for development experience
- Team training and mentoring (Git branching Workflows, DevOps Tools, Curio, Design Patterns, Java Android Dev, Functional Programming, Angular 1.x)

OSS PROJECTS

LANGUAGES

Portuguese •••••
English ••••0

Project Leader

Mar 2012 - Present

Architect and Lead developer of **SCENE** (https://github.com/pextralabs/scene-platform) a rule-based situation recognition platform on top of the JBoss Drools rule engine.

EDUCATION

Federal University of Espirito Santo, Master of Informatics

Vitória, ES, Brazil

Feb 2017 - Present

Research on Context-aware application development techniques, Quality of Context(QoC) and Situation-awareness.

Architect and Lead developer of the <u>Scene Platform</u>, a rule-based framework for situation-aware application development.

Co-author of 4 research papers and a book chapter about those subjects. One of them \underline{A} rule-based platform for situation management) awarded with the Best Paper award at the IEEE CogSIMA 2013 Conference.

Federal University of Espirito Santo, Bachelor of Computer Science

Vitória, ES, Brazil

Feb 2006 - Feb 2012

COURSES

Functional Programming in Scala Specialization, École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne via Coursera

Feb 2016 - Feb 2017

SCIENTIFIC PUBLICATIONS

Rule-Based Support for Situation Management

Jan 2016

book chapter for Springer's Fusion Methodologies in Crisis Management - 2016

An Infrastructure for Distributed Rule-based Situation San Antonio - TX, USA Management

Feb 2014

<u>conference paper</u> for IEEE International Multi-Disciplinary Cognitive Methods in Situation Awareness and Decision Support (CogSIMA) - 2014

Um Serviço de Gerenciamento de Qualidade de Contexto em Redes de Sensores sem Fio

Porto Alegre - RS, Brazil

Nov 2013

<u>conference paper</u> for Conferência Ibero Americana de Computação Aplicada (CIACA) - 2013

A Rule-based Platform for Situation Management

San Diego - CA, USA

Feb 2013

<u>conference paper</u> for IEEE International Multi-Disciplinary Cognitive Methods in Situation Awareness and Decision Support (CogSIMA) - 2013

Beijing, China

A Model-Driven Approach to Situations: Situation Modeling and Rule-Based Situation Detection Sep 2012

<u>conference paper</u> for IEEE International Enterprise Distributed Object Computing Conference (EDOC) -2012